Redwood Canyon Ramblers collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 2: Event recordings and related materials
  - Japan tour: train ride - Redwood Canyon Ramblers, April 30, 1991, April 31, 1990; AFC 2011/011: SR52
    - Sound recording (cut-level), rcr1991-04-30at01.aif - rcr1991-04-30at06.aif; 6 sound files: high-resolution files, digital (.aif)
      Discussion of integrating the histories and these parallels into the presentation discussion of regional/southern identity 00:04:23
      Neil and Mayne: rock and roll as commercial hype/politics of this music 00:04:34
      Toru discusses politics of music/"You Are My Sunshine" context 00:05:21
    - Song list and production notes for SR52, February 7, 2013, rcr1991-04-30a.txt; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.txt)
    - Typed song list, with counter numbers from the tape deck, July 2, 1991, May 20, 2011, 1991 Japan Trip Cassette Notes.pdf; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.pdf)
  - Japan tour: Nakajima residence, near Fukuoka on Kyushu - Redwood Canyon Ramblers, April 30, 1991, AFC 2011/011: SR53
    - Sound recording (cut-level), rcr1991-04-30bt01.aif - rcr1991-04-30bt23.aif; 23 sound files: high-resolution files, digital (.aif)
      Tape 2A
      Neil and Mayne discuss treatment of leftist folkies and Mayne's interrogation/discussion of the draft 00:09:19
      Discussion of current attitude of Americans toward bluegrass music 00:09:10
      Discussion of religion in bluegrass 00:08:23
      Bluegrass and dancing/KPFA 00:04:15
      Nakajima family band history and talk about their instruments 00:05:59
      "My Heart Skips A Beat" 00:03:09
      "Teardrops In My Eyes" 00:04:21
      "Washington County" 00:02:39
      Tape 2B
      Discussion of the Nakajima family band's talent/koto banjo tuning 00:04:47
      Banjo tune 00:03:29
      "Haranomu" [banjo and violin] 00:04:29
      "Sakura" [clawhammer banjo] 00:02:43
      "I Feel Fine" 00:03:20
      "Devil's Dream" 00:02:46
      "Rocky Top" 00:03:32
      "What A Friend We Have In Jesus" 00:05:24
      "Orange Blossom Special" 00:05:10
      "Going Down The Road Feeling Bad" #1 00:02:39
      "Going Down The Road Feeling Bad" #2 00:02:20
      Tape 3A
      "Little Maggie" 00:03:47
      "If I Lose" 00:03:07
      "Pike County Breakdown" 00:03:07
      "Angel Band" 00:04:31
    - Song list and production notes for SR53, November 6, 2011, rcr1991-04-30b.txt; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.txt)
    - Typed song list, with counter numbers from the tape deck, July 2, 1991, May 20, 2011, 1991 Japan Trip Cassette Notes.pdf; 1 manuscript: color, digital (.pdf)
  - Japan tour - Redwood Canyon Ramblers, May 5, 1991, May 11, 1991, AFC 2011/011: SR55
    - Sound recording (cut-level), rcr1991-05-11t01.aif - rcr1991-05-11t11.aif; 11 sound files: high-resolution files, digital (.aif)
      Tape 1A
      Recorded at Shin Kobe Hotel (May 5, 1991).
      Early sketch of Mayne's song "Dateline Ramble" 00:03:34
      Tape 4A
      Nentsuji Temple at Kamaishi, Gifu dinner and performance gathering (May 11, 1991).
      Tuning and chat 00:04:22
      Banjo and bass duet [Neil and Tsudasan] 00:01:43
      Old-time fiddle and mandolin 00:05:34
      Mandolin trio tune 00:02:48
      "Blackberry Blossom" [same trio] 00:03:49
      "Give The Fiddler A Dram" [same trio] 00:03:59
      Mayne and Toru discuss next day plans and performance 00:04:38
      Focus shifts to another mandolin trio that's been playing underneath the chat 00:05:18
      More mandolin jam with Ed Neff now playing 00:01:49
      "Arkansas Traveler" [new group jam with Neil now playing] 00:07:56
    - Song list and production notes for SR55, November 6, 2011, rcr1991-05-11.txt; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.txt)
    - Typed song list, with counter numbers from the tape deck, July 2, 1991, May 20, 2011, 1991 Japan Trip Cassette Notes.pdf; 1 manuscript: color, digital (.pdf)
  - "Studio Today: Let's Talk Hot" (live), on Radio Kansai, May 6, 1991, AFC 2011/011: SR14
    - Sound recording (full), AFC 2011/011: SR14; RYP 7391; 1 sound cassette (Side 1: 00:46:34, Side 2: 00:28:14): analog, 1 7/8 ips, Type I, stereo.
      Recorded live on Radio Kansai, Kobe, Hyogo, Japan. 10:15-11:30 AM. MCs: The Saijo twins. Music by members of the Redwood Canyon Ramblers (Mayne Smith, Neil Rosenberg, Ed Neff). Talk: Toru Mitsui. The MCs talk over the intro and at various points during the songs played. Songs, interview segments, and commercials are interspersed. Most of the interview is in Japanese, with some parts in English.
      Archivist's note: While AFC has the source tape, digital files made by LC from the source tape, and the digital files received from Brian Miksis, the elapsed times were used rather than real-time markers. See SR54 for the edited version of this tape.
      Original Rosenberg inventory number: tape 288.
    - Sound recording (cut-level), rcr1991-05-06t01.aif - rcr1991-05-06t30.aif; 30 sound files: high-resolution files, digital (.aif)
      Bumper [brief announcement] 00:00:26
      Show intro/"Jesse James" 00:02:44
      Discussion [Japanese] 00:02:32
      Commercial 00:00:34
      Discussion/band introductions [Japanese/English] 00:07:19
      Commercials 00:01:43
      Song intro [Japanese] 00:01:21
      "Golden Slippers" 00:02:18
      Discussion [Japanese] 00:04:17
      Commercials 00:01:33
      Song intro 00:01:02
      "I Saw The Light" 00:03:07
      Discussion [Japanese] 00:00:43
      Commercials 00:01:03
      Discussion with band members [Japanese/English] 00:06:12
      Commercials 00:00:46
      Song intro 00:00:49
      "On My Way To The Old Home" 00:02:51
      Discussion [Japanese] 00:03:09
      Commercials 00:01:22
      Commercials 00:05:27
      Song intro 00:01:31
      "Foggy Mountain Breakdown" 00:02:24
      Discussion/song intro [Japanese] 00:02:07
      "Angel Band" 00:03:56
      Discussion [Japanese] 00:00:56
      Commercials 00:01:59
      Discussion [Japanese] 00:06:41
      Show outro/"The Gold Rush" 00:02:46
      Woman announcer voice 00:00:06
    - Song list and production notes for SR14, January 10, 2011, rcr1991-05-06.txt; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.txt)
    - Typed song list and event details on the cassette J-card, circa 1991, rcr1991-05-06 _Reel 288_.pdf; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.pdf)
  - "Studio Today: Let's Talk Hot" (live), on Radio Kansai (edited version), May 6, 1991, AFC 2011/011: SR54
    Archivist's note: This was sent to AFC as an edited version of SR14, meant to focus on the English-language portions of the program.
    - Sound recording (cut-level), 01 Show Intro -_ Jesse James.aif, 02 discussion_band intros _Japanese_English_.aif, 03 Golden Slippers.aif, 04 I Saw The Light.aif, 05 discussion with band members _Japanese_English_.aif, 06 On My Way Back To The Old Home.aif, 07 discussion _Japanese_.aif, 08 Foggy Mountain Breakdown.aif, 09 Angel Band.aif, 10 Show Outro_The Gold Rush.aif; 10 sound files: high-resolution files, digital (.aif)
  - Concert-lecture at Hamamatsu - Toru Mitsumi, host and lecturer; Redwood Canyon Ramblers, May 9, 1991, AFC 2011/011: MV02
    - Video recording (full), AFC 2011/011: MV02; 1 videocassette (VHS): sound, color; 1/2 in.
    - Video recording (cut-level), rcr1991-05-09v1.mov, rcr1991-05-09v2.mov; 2 video files: sound, color, digital (.mov)
      The digital files were created from a VHS copy, thought to have been made by the Hamamatsu Civic Cultural Center staff.
      "Home Sweet Home"
      "Bury Me Beneath the Willow"
      Toru: general introduction and explanation of the background of the Ramblers' music, starting with the British isles
      "House Carpenter"
      Toru: African roots
      "Take This Hammer"
      Toru: minstrel shows
      "Golden Slippers" [instrumental]
      Toru
      "Froggie Went a-Courting"
      Toru: the American West
      "Goodbye Old Pal" [lead vocal by Ed]
      "Before I Met You"
      "Redwing" [instrumental]
      Intermission [recorded off/on]
      Toru introduces Ed
      "I'm On My Way Back to the Old Home" [lead vocal by Ed]
      Toru asks Ed about design Of mandolin and fiddle
      "Soldier's Joy" [banjo and fiddle only]
      Toru asks Ed about his musical biography
      Toru asks Neil about the origin of the banjo
      "Foggy Mountain Breakdown"
      Toru asks Neil about his musical biography
      "Amelia Earhart's Last Flight" [vocal by Neil; Mayne on dobro]
      Toru asks Mayne about design of the dobro
      "I Saw the Light "
      Momiyama switches to fiddle and the RCR are joined by unidentified musicians on bass, guitar, and dobro
      "You Are My Sunshine" [Toru sings lead on two verses]
      "Will the Circle Be Unbroken"
      "Jesse James"
      All leave the stage to applause. The RCR return, with bassist number two and Momiyama on fiddle
      "Little Maggie"
      End
    - Content list and production notes for MV02, undated, rcr1991-05-09.pdf; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.pdf)
  - Japan tour: Kenzawa University lecture (English edit) - Redwood Canyon Ramblers, May 13, 1991, AFC 2011/011: SR56
    - Sound recording (cut-level), rcr1991-05-13t01.aif - rcr1991-05-13t10.aif; 10 sound files: high-resolution files, digital (.aif)
      Archivist's note: a pre-tagged CD file was not received for track 10.
      Tape 4B
      Toru introduction to audience 00:04:13
      Neil greeting and talk about slavery 00:06:38
      Distinctions between European and African music 00:05:39
      Post Civil War music reintegration 00:05:50
      Copying black style becomes popular in white music 00:05:19
      Discussing personal experience growing up white next to Oakland 00:08:07
      Question about marketing black music to whites 00:02:32
      Neil discusses economic power of teens/Mayne discusses cars and radio to teen exposure 00:04:43
      Question and discussion of post WWII and black migration for work 00:01:59
      Question and discussion of music as a complex event with different experiences between artists and audience 00:01:19
    - Song list and production notes for SR56, November 6, 2011, rcr1991-05-13.txt; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.txt)
    - Typed song list, with counter numbers from the tape deck, July 2, 1991, May 20, 2011, 1991 Japan Trip Cassette Notes.pdf; 1 manuscript: color, digital (.pdf)
  - Redwood Canyon Ramblers at Freight and Salvage Coffeehouse, May 15, 1991, AFC 2011/011: SR15
    - Sound recording (full), AFC 2011/011: SR15; RYP 7392; 1 sound cassette (Side 1: 00:57:10, Side 2: 00:47:44): analog, 1 7/8 ips, Type IV, stereo.
      Recorded live at Freight and Salvage, 1111 Addison St., Berkeley, California. Personnel: Scott Hambly, Neil Rosenberg, Mayne Smith, Ed Neff, Larry Cohea.
      Original Rosenberg inventory number: tape 289.
    - Sound recording (cut-level), rcr1991-05-15t01.aif - rcr1991-05-15t28.aif; 28 sound files: high-resolution files, digital (.aif)
      Introduction by Sandy Rothman/playback of Campbell Coe from 1960 00:04:27
      "Auld Lang Syne" 00:03:25
      "Out In The Cold World"/"Wandering Boy" 00:02:44
      Introductions: Mayne Smith, guitar; Scott Hambly, mandolin; Ed Neff, fiddle and mandolin; Steve Patier, bass; another member of the band is the sound engineer 00:01:57
      "House Carpenter" 00:06:17
      "Good Woman's Love" 00:03:26
      "Bury Me Beneath The Willow" 00:03:58
      "Golden Slippers" 00:04:06
      "Amelia Earhart" 00:04:50
      "Goodbye Old Pal" 00:02:40
      "Back In The Saddle Again" 00:02:52
      Introduction/tuning to "Dateline Ramble" 00:01:58
      "Dateline Ramble" [sung in English and Japanese] 00:03:16
      "Angel Band" [strange repeat/edit moment in beginning] 00:05:19
      "Boston Burglar" [cassette side change] 00:04:06
      "Riding The Midnight Train" [the recording begins with the song in progress] 00:02:54
      "Columbus Stockade Blues" 00:03:21
      "Pike County Breakdown" 00:03:08
      "Froggy Went A'Courtin'" 00:04:11
      "After Dark" 00:03:37
      "Little Willie" 00:04:14
      "Time Clock Of Life" 00:03:24
      "Down In The Willow Garden" 00:03:19
      "Take This Hammer" 00:04:19
      "Red River Valley" 00:02:32
      Various people are named and thanked 00:03:14
      "Jesse James" 00:04:57
      "I Saw The Light" [encore] 00:03:11
    - Song list and production notes for SR15, January 11, 2011, rcr1991-05-15.txt; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.txt)
    - Cassette j-card with handwritten song list, circa 1991, rcr1991-05-15 _Reel 289_.pdf; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.pdf)
  - Redwood Canyon Ramblers at Freight and Salvage Coffeehouse, June 17, 1993, AFC 2011/011: SR16
    - Sound recording (full), AFC 2011/011: SR16; RYP 7393; 1 sound cassette (Side 1: 00:46:47, Side 2: 00:15:26): analog, 1 7/8, Type II, stereo.
      Recorded at Freight and Salvage Coffeehouse, 1111 Addison St., Berkeley, California. Personnel: Scott Hambly, Neil Rosenberg, Mayne Smith, Julie Smolin, Larry Cohea, Leroy McNee).
      Original Rosenberg inventory number: tape 290.
    - Sound recording (cut-level), rcr1993-06-17t01.aif - rcr1993-06-17t16.aif; 16 sound files: high-resolution files, digital (.aif)
      "Jesse James" 00:03:28
      "Back In The Saddle Again" 00:02:35
      Mayne Smith introduces band members Scott Hambly and Neil Rosenberg (banjo) and describes the evolution of the Redwood Canyon Ramblers, and well-known musicians present. 00:03:17
      "Little Willie" 00:05:55
      "Good Woman's Love" 00:02:58
      "Your Love Is Like A Flower" 00:04:10
      "Love Of The Mountains" 00:04:16
      "Soldier's Joy"/"Amelia Earhart" [false start] 00:03:13
      "Amelia Earhart" 00:03:48
      "Foggy Mountain Rock" 00:01:53
      "Willow Garden" 00:04:01
      "House Carpenter" [cassette side change] 00:06:26
      "Pike County Breakdown" 00:03:26
      "Footprints In The Snow" 00:04:17
      "Angel Band" 00:04:42
      "Bury Me Beneath The Willow" 00:02:56
    - Song list and production notes for SR16, January 11, 2011, rcr1993-06-17.txt; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.txt)
    - Handwritten song list on the cassette J-card, circa 1993, rcr1993-06-17 _Reel 290_.pdf; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.pdf)
    - Redwood Canyon Ramblers in concert, June 17, 1993, 1993-06-17.jpg; 1 photograph: color, digital (.jpg)
      Left to right: Julie Smolin, Neil V. Rosenberg, Leroy McNees, Larry Cohea, Scott Hambly, Mayne Smith
  - Reunion jam, Mayne Smith's residence, Richmond, California - Redwood Canyon Ramblers, August 4, 1997, AFC 2011/011: MV01
    - Video recording (full), AFC 2011/011: MV01; VAS 4719; 1 videocassette (VHS): sound, color; 1/2 in.
      Only the first part of the recording has both audio and video; the last two sections are audio only. The original recording was made on Hi8, and the VHS copy is a slightly edited version of that recording.
    - Video recording (full), rcr1997-08-04v.mov; 1 video file: sound, color, digital (.mov)
    - Sound recording (cut-level), rcr1997-08-04t01.aif - rcr1997-08-04t25.aif; 25 sound files: high-resolution files, digital (.aif)
      Part 1
      Digitized from Hi8.
      "Fireball Mail" [begins in progress] 00:04:32
      "Reuben" 00:06:51
      "I Wonder Where You Are Tonight"/Sandy's frozen capo/Lundberg strings joke 00:06:24
      "Jesse James" 00:03:29
      Discussion of "Jesse James" verses/discussion of prisoner's right/last day on earth/National guitars 00:04:21
      "After Dark"/refinishing Mayne's guitar 00:04:35
      "Good Woman's Love" 00:02:56
      Discussion of Gene Tortora/taking a break 00:04:29
      Part 2
      Digitized from Hi8. Performed indoors as audio only.
      "Riding That Midnight Train" [begins in progress]/beer break 00:02:49
      Discussion of Neil's old family home/Jimmie Rogers tribute album produced by Bob Dylan 00:05:01
      "Red Apple Juice"/Neil playing duct tape as rhythm instrument 00:06:22
      "Bury Me Beneath The Willow"/discussion of Barry Olivier 00:05:36
      "House Carpenter" 00:05:23
      Discussion of October 1990 demo session and arrangement/history of "House Carpenter" 00:04:52
      "Hand Me Down My Walking Cane"/beer break 00:06:10
      Book about southern bluegrass movement/discussion of Clarence White/Mayne discusses 1966 UCLA 1/2 hour film about Kentucky Colonels/discussion of archiving formats/Mayne's session with Taj Mahal, Richard Greene with Paul Rothchild 00:08:52
      Advancement of media technology 00:11:25
      "Down In The Willow Garden"/discussion of women and murder ballads/"Doc and Dawg" CD 00:06:56
      "Banjolina"/discussion of Bobby Thompson, Don Reno 00:04:05
      Discussion of David Nadel/politics of the Freight and Salvage 00:07:14
      "Molly And Tenbrooks" 00:03:16
      Part 3
      Digitized from Mayne Smith's VHS copy.
      Discussion of Earl and Louise Scruggs 00:10:01
      "Wreck Of The Old '97"/discuss playing "Mojave Wind" 00:05:20
      "Mojave Wind" 00:04:46
      Discussion of camping trip that inspired the song 00:04:20
    - Content list and production notes for MV01, rcr1997-08-04.txt; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.txt)
    - Annotated content list, RCR 970804.pdf; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.pdf)
  - Second reunion jam, Mayne Smith's residence, Richmond, California - Redwood Canyon Ramblers, August 6, 1997, AFC 2011/011: MV03
    - Video recording (full), rcr1997-08-06v.mov; 1 video file: sound, color, digital (.mov)
      The original recording was made on Hi8. The sound recordings are cut-level digital copies of the audio from the video.
    - Sound recording (cut-level) (audio only), rcr1997-08-06t01.aif - rcr1997-08-06t20.aif; 20 sound files: high-resolution files, digital (.aif)
      "How Mountain Girls Can Love" [begins in progress] 00:00:57
      "Angel Band" [begins in progress] 00:01:10
      Neil discusses an old family guitar/improved quality of Gibson instruments 00:04:32
      "Down In The Willow Garden" 00:04:03
      "East Virginia"/discussion of Walter Hensley 00:05:28
      "Mansion On The Hill" 00:03:21
      Mayne discusses how early days with RCR influenced his whole style/writing a book/Katie Hambly's history within the folk scene 00:05:22
      Discussion of Chuck Berry/tuning and false starts of next tune 00:04:26
      "I Want To Be Loved (But Only By You)"/discussion about banjo tone 00:04:48
      Mayne's 1952 Martin D-18 modifications/Hideo's shop 00:09:01
      Sandy Rothman and early RCR history/Sandy arrives 00:10:35
      "Boston Burglar" 00:05:31
      Discussion of Robert Cantwell 00:04:31
      "I Want A Girl (Just Like The Girl)" 00:03:29
      "Golden Slippers"/"ralphing" example 00:05:11
      "Angel Band" 00:08:54
      "Roving Gambler" [Mayne on dobro]/discussion of different versions 00:08:19
      "Letters Have No Arms" [Mayne on dobro] 00:06:10
      "Satisfied Mind"/Mayne demonstrates the version he recorded 00:06:19
      Porter Wagoner discussion/Osborne Brothers/baldness in performing/"Reuben's Train" tease/returning Sandy's banjo 00:10:34
    - Content list and production notes for MV03, undated, rcr1997-08-06.txt; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.txt)
    - Annotated song list, undated, RCR 970806.pdf; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.pdf)
  - Celebration of the musical career of Mayne Smith at Freight and Salvage, Berkeley, California, June 20, 2008, AFC 2011/011: MV04
    - Video recording (full), rcr2008-06-20v.mov; 1 video file: sound, color, digital (.mov)
    - Sound recording (cut-level), rcr2008-06-20t01.wav - rcr2008-06-20t17.wav, ms2008-06-20t01.wav - ms2008-06-20t15.wav; 32 sound files: high-resolution files, digital (.wav)
      Set 1 - Redwood Canyon Ramblers
      Introductions 00:03:46
      "Jesse James" 00:03:49
      "Back To The Old Highway" 00:03:18
      "On My Way Back To The Old Home" 00:04:14
      "It's Not Time To Go" 00:05:33
      "Dateline Ramble" 00:04:45
      "Sioux City Sue" 00:04:42
      "I'm Still Hungry" [with Eric Thompson on guitar] 00:05:17
      "House Carpenter" [with Eric Thompson on guitar] 00:05:17
      Sound check 00:21:31
      Talk/tuning 00:03:42
      "Jesse James" 00:03:33
      Talk/tuning 00:03:12
      "House Carpenter" 00:02:12
      Talk/tuning 00:01:14
      "Dateline Ramble" 00:02:15
      Talk/tuning 00:01:12
      "I'm Still Hungry" 00:04:11
      Set 2 - Mayne Smith
      "Let The Good Love Flow" 00:05:34
      "They'll Know Who I Am" 00:04:28
      "Saturday 6 A.M." 00:06:38
      "Mojave Wind" 00:07:07
      "Slave To A Six-String Guitar" 00:08:30
      "My Dancing Days" 00:07:25
      "Letting People Go" 00:08:48
      "My Heart's Content" 00:03:20
      Set 3 - Mayne Smith
      "Careless Love Again" 00:05:51
      "I Like It" 00:04:20
      "Saturday Matinee" 00:07:47
      "Home Away From Home" 00:07:29
      "Solitaire" 00:05:15
      "To Each His Own" 00:07:33
      "TransAtlantic Blues" 00:05:56
    - Content lists and production notes for MV04, June 24, 2008, rcr-2008-06-20.txt (set 1), ms2008-06-20.txt (sets 2 and 3); 2 manuscripts: black and white, digital (.txt)
  - Redwood Canyon Ramblers family jam in Mayne Smith's living room, Richmond, California, November 29, 2009, AFC 2011/011: MV05
    - Video recording (full), rcr2009-11-29v.mov; 1 video file: sound, color, digital (.mov)
    - Sound recording (cut-level), rcr2009-11-29t01.aif - rcr2009-11-29t08.aif; 8 sound files: high-resolution files, digital (.wav)
      "Little Willy" 00:04:44
      "Snow Dove" 00:03:33
      "Good Woman's Love" 00:03:33
      "Bonaparte's Retreat" 00:01:44
      "Busted" 00:03:31
      Dolly Parton joke 00:01:35
      "Twilight Time" [fragment played by Neil Rosenberg] 00:01:25
      "Never On Sunday" [Neil and Terri Thomson] 00:01:36
    - Content list and production notes for MV05, undated, rcr2009-11-29.txt; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.txt)
    - Mayne Smith's recollections about the jam and the circumstances, undated, 2009-11-29-Maynes notes.txt; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.txt)
  - Additional digital surrogates of selected recordings in Series 2, afc2011011_dc001
    - Medium resolution derivatives of digitized sound recordings, 825 sound files: digital (.aif)
      Digitized by Brian Miksis from selected tapes and resized to medium-resolution CD pre-tagged (aif) versions.
    - Low resolution derivatives of digitized sound recordings, 835 sound files: digital (.mp3)
      Digitized by Brian Miksis from selected tapes and resized to low-resolution mp3 pre-tagged (mp3) versions.
    - Additional digitized sound recordings, 268 sound files: digital (.aif, .wav)
    - DVD disk images of digitized video recordings, 4 video files: sound, color, digital (.img)
      Digitized by Brian Miksis from selected tapes and reformatted as pre-authored DVDs with chapter marks.
- Series 3: Photographic materials
  Photographs of the band, both in concert and in casual settings, probably as publicity shots.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Redwood Canyon Ramblers, in Berkeley, California, August 1959, Shelby Sampson; 1959-08-00 RCR by SS 1.jpg; 1 photograph: black and white, digital (.jpg)
  - Redwood Canyon Ramblers, in Berkeley, California, August 1959, Shelby Sampson; 1959-08-00 RCR by SS 2.jpg; 1 photograph: black and white, digital (.jpg)
  - Redwood Canyon Ramblers, in Berkeley, California, August 1959, Shelby Sampson; 1959-08-00 RCR by SS 3.jpg; 1 photograph: black and white, digital (.jpg)
  - Redwood Canyon Ramblers, outside Scott Hambly's house, August 1959, 1959-08-00 RCR at SHs 1.jpg; 1 photograph: black and white, digital (.jpg)
  - Redwood Canyon Ramblers, outside Scott Hambly's house, August 1959, 1959-08-00 RCR at SHs 2.jpg; 1 photograph: black and white, digital (.jpg)